Richard Blankenhorn

4400 S Monaco Street, Denver, CO 80237 | T 314-712-2355 | rsbnq6@yahoo.com |

Objective

After spending several years in the financial services industry, I have decided to pursue my passion and transition in to a more challenging and rewarding career in development/analytics. I am looking to obtain a junior developer/analyst role under the mentorship of a senior analyst/developer.

Toolbox

- Web Development: Ruby on Rails, RSpec, TDD, HTML, CSS, JQuery, Bootstrap
- · Analytics: Python, R, SAS, SQL
- Development Tools: RubyMine, PyCharm, Git & GitHub, R Studio, SAS Studio, SQL Developer, Shell/CL, Pivotal Tracker

Education

- Dakota State University Masters in Data Analytics 2015 2017
- · DaVinci Coders Building the Toolbelt of a Junior Ruby on Rails Engineer
- University of Missouri Columbia BSBA Finance
- · Series 7 and 63 Licensed

Projects & Code

GitHub: https://github.com/RichardBlankenhorn Resume App: richardblankenhorn-resume.herokuapp.com

Codeeval: https://www.codeeval.com/profile/rblank25/

Work Experience

Financial Services Representative II (Senior Broker): Scottrade, Inc 2011 - Present

- Analyze and implement option expiration reports to mitigate risk to the firm. Involves thorough understanding of margin call
 risk, buying power calculations and overall risk to the client and the firm based upon current and expiring option positions
 (long calls, long puts and naked put options).
- Research and analyze impact to client's tax situation due to mandatory reorganizations such as mergers, splits and spinoffs.
 Assist clients with cost basis calculations and overall impact to their Form 1099.
- Develop and implement effective learning methods to prepare new hires for their series 7 & 63 exams and to obtain a comprehensive understanding of their roles.

Financial Services Representative: Scottrade, Inc 2009 - 2011

- · Assist clients with meeting their financial objectives through a better understanding of financial products and investment risks.
- Provide clients with a better understanding of our online tools and resources.
- Assist clients via phone, chat and e-mail with opening accounts, placing trades, deposits and account navigation. Answer
 general questions related to investment product availability, account services, tax preparation and policy

Mutual Fund Networking: Scottrade, Inc 2006 - 2009

- Run daily reports for mutual fund transfers, networking and reconciliation
- Facilitate transfers between Scottrade and mutual fund companies. Assist branch network and service center with mutual fund trades, fund requirements, product availability, internal transfers and mutual fund networking.